Lestoque, Albert; Papers ger059
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Writings of Albert Lestoque, 1909-1960; 4; 149 file folders
  - Belletristic writings, Undated; 4.1; 73 file folders
    - Menschen in Aktendeckeln. Handwritten manuscript, in German of Lestoque's published novel, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 13)
    - Menschen in Aktendeckeln. Synopsis, in English, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 14)
    - Menschen in Aktendeckeln. Reviews, 1939-1943; typescripts and clippings (Box 3 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 15)
    - Menschen in Aktendeckeln, 1939-1940 (Box 3 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 16)
      Correspondence concerning translation from German into English.
      Includes letters from Franzi Ascher and Karl Jakob Hirsch.
    - Menschen in Aktendeckeln. Correspondence with Alliance Book Corporation (Milton S. Pratiner), 1939-1940 (Box 3 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 17)
    - Menschen in Aktendeckeln. Correspondence with Veit Wyler concerning German publication, 1939-1952 (Box 3 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 18)
    - Fates on File. English translation of Menschen in Aktendeckeln, Undated; typescript (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 1)
    - Fates on File. Typescript of Parts III and IV, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 2)
    - Fates on File. Extra typescript pages, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 3)
    - "Der Mörder. Novelle", Undated; carbon typescript (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 4)
    - Sprünge am Abgrund, Undated; carbon typescript (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 5)
    - Sprünge am Abgrund, Undated; 4 copies (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 6-7)
    - Justice (English translation of Sprünge am Abgrund.) Synopsis, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 8)
    - "Der Steuersteckbrief". Partial typescript, in German, pp. 28-131. Accompanied to a letter by Lestoque to his mother, 1939 (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 9)
    - Novel fragments, Undated; manuscripts and typescripts (Box 4 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 10)
    - Playscripts and sketches, Undated; 4.1.29
      - "Agariste". Play manuscript, dedicated to "meinem lieben Bruder Paul", Undated (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 11)
      - "Wie ich um meinen ersten dichterischen Erfolg gekommen bin". Statement about the play "Agariste", Undated (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 12)
      - Der Asra. Schauspiel in 3 Akten, 1920; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 13)
        Also copy of published playscript.
      - "Der Aufstieg. Ein Weltgeschehen (Weltdrama) in drei Aufzügen", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 14)
      - "Der Fakir. Ein Weltgeschehen (Weltdrama) in drei Aufzügen". Alternate title for "Der Aufstieg", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 15)
      - "Flirt", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 16)
      - "Grosse Zeit. Schauspiel in einem Akt", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 17)
      - "Ilse Ausserland (Die Mimose)", undated; manuscript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 18)
      - "Der Rach... Drama in 3 Aufzügen", undated; manuscript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 19)
      - "Die Treppe. Schauspiel", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 20)
      - "Der Weg", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 21)
      - Untitled play sketches, undated; typescript and manuscript (Box 4 (4.1.29-Playscripts and sketches), Folder 22)
    - Poetry, Undated; 4.1.30
      - Poems, dedicated by Albert Lestoque to his mother, 1909-1917; typescript and handwritten (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 23)
      - Early poetry, ca. 1910-1914; manuscript (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 24)
      - Typescripts of poems with titles, undated (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 25)
      - Typescripts of poems, untitled, undated (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 26)
      - Poems, dated 1909-1917 (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 27)
        Primarily typescripts.
      - Collection of poems, typed, undated (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 28)
      - "Liebesfrühling. Gedichte". Collection of poems, typed, 1916 (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 29)
      - "Der Page. Lieder der Sehnsucht". Collection of poems, typed, 1920s (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 30)
      - "Zur Laute". Song lyrics, 1923 July (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 31)
      - Poems, untitled, handwritten, ca. 1920-1930 (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 32)
      - Poems, titled, typewritten, ca. 1920-1930 (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 33)
      - Poetry, mostly typewritten, ca. 1940-1956 (Box 4 (4.1.30-Poetry), Folder 34)
    - Short prose works, stories, Undated; 4.1.31
      - Early prose, primarily handwritten, in German, undated (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 35)
      - Short prose pieces, typed and handwritten, in German, ca. 1914 (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 36)
      - "Auferstehung des Fleisches", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 37)
      - "Bobsley. Eine Skizze aus Klosers", undated (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 38)
        Manuscript and typescript versions.
      - "Das Fest der Sträflinge", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 39)
      - "Der Herr aus Leichlingen", undated; manuscript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 40)
      - "Das Kleeblatt", 1916 March 15; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 41)
      - "Der Mörder", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 42)
      - "Thea Cordia. Tagebuchblätter eines Liebenden", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 43)
      - Untitled story, undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 44)
      - "An Evening with a German Girl", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 45)
      - "Cocktailparties [sic!]", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 46)
      - "King", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 47)
      - "Sunday in January or: Sunday Arithmetic", undated; typescript (Box 4 (4.1.31-Short prose works, stories), Folder 48)
  - Essayistic writings, Undated; 4.2; 76 file folders
    This series has been divided into two sections. The first section contains early published writings of Albert Lestoque, written in German and primarily on the subjects of prison conditions and penal reform, as well as clippings, case files and other research materials used by him to research these topics. The second section of this series contains texts of both lectures and essayistic publications, primarily written by Lestoque in English after immigrating to the United States.
    The first section arranged chronologically and the remainder alphabetically.
    - Clippings and offprints of early articles, Undated; 4.2.1
      - "Das Boehle-Buch". Clipping, 1925 February 28 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 1)
      - "Kriegspropaganda!" Clipping, 1927 February 28 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 2)
      - "Zur Strafrechtsreform". Clipping, unsigned, 1927 March 31 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 3)
      - "Strafrechtsreform". Offprint, 1927 November 25 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 4)
      - "Rachejustiz und Strafvollzug", 1927 December 9; typescript and offprint (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 5)
      - "Welche praktische Bedeutung haben die Berichte der sozialen Gerichtshilfe für die Urteilsfindung?" Offprint, 1928 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 6)
      - "Gedanken zur Strafrechtsreform", ca. 1928; typescript (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 7)
      - "Mädchenhandel". Clipping, 1928 January 9 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 8)
      - "Der Rückfall als Strafmilderungsgrund". Offprint, 1928 February 17 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 9)
      - "Um das neue Recht". Clipping, 1928 March 9 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 10)
      - "Neue Wege im Strafvollzug. Bericht über eine Frankfurter Tagung des Verbandes der Strafanstalts-Oberbeamten". Clipping, 1928 March 14 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 11)
      - "Gegen die Todesstrafe". Offprint, 1928 October 19 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 12)
      - "Die Rechtlosigkeit der Untersuchungsgefangenen". Offprint, 1929 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 13)
      - "Der Schutz der persönlichen Freiheit?" Offprint, 1929 January 11 (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 14)
      - "Die Bedeutung der Freiheitsstrafe", 1929 February 5; typescript (Box 5 (4.2.1-Clippings and offprints of early articles), Folder 15)
    - "Gefangene". Handwritten autobiographies by prisoners, Undated (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 16)
    - Clippings on the topics of juvenile delinquency, social conditions, prisons, 1925-1931 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 17)
    - "Polizeimißhandlungen". Clippings and notes, 1926-1932 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 18)
    - Case file: Mathilde Fehl vs. Vogler, 1930-1931 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 19)
    - Case file: Frau Kolomak Case, 1927 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1920s-1930s (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 21)
    - "Schedule of Lectures, 1943-1945", Undated; typed list (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 22)
    - "A Formula for Permanent Peace", 1951 May 7; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 23)
    - "Address at Thanksgiving Kiwanis Club". Typescript of lecture, American Association of University Women, 1945 November 8 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 24)
    - "American by Choice", 1944 May 21 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 25)
      Typescript of speech, programs, clippings.
    - "An American Rescues Victims of Nazi Terror in France", early 1940s; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 26)
    - "Ansprüche amerikanischer Bürger wegen Kriegsschäden". Clipping, 1956 July 20 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 27)
    - "As Johnson Sees It". Clipping, 1951 May 20 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 28)
    - "Becker -- Huber -- Küster, Bundesentschädigungsgesetz", 1956 March; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 29)
    - "Can Punishment Cure Juvenile Delinquency?", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 30)
    - "Crime and Punishment". Clipping, 1952 August 8 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 31)
    - "Criminal Laws with Retroactive Force and the Nuremberg Trial", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 32)
    - "Danger Spot -- Iran". Clipping, 1951 March 18 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 33)
    - "Denmark Before the War and Nowadays", 1944 February 14; typescript of lecture (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 34)
    - "Desiré. Indiskretion eines Kammerdieners". Film review, Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 35)
    - "Ein Millionär reformiert den Strafvollzug", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 36)
      (review of Leonard V. Harrison, Pryor McNeill Grant, Jugend in Fesseln, 1938).
    - "European Impressions". Typescript of lecture, 1947 January 11 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 37)
    - "For a Foreign Legion" (letter to the editor). Clipping, 1951 February 24 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 38)
    - " æFree Enterprise' in Western Germany", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 39)
    - "The French-German Situation", 1950 April 14; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 40)
      Version in French, entitled "La Situation Franco-Allemande". Typescript with numerous h. corr., undated.
    - "The German Mind in Action". Several versions, Undated [ca. 1948-1950]; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 41)
    - "The Germans Want a King", ca. 1955; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 42)
    - "Godesberg Purchase", 1952 July 4; typescript and clipping (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 43)
    - "Government Under Hitler". Typescript of lecture text, 1944 February 12 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 44)
    - "How to make Democracy live". Typescript and notes, Undated (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 45)
    - "How to Write a Novel". Typescript of lecture, 1946 February 18 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 46)
    - "Impressions of Europe". Typescript of lecture, 1951 November 3 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 47)
    - "In memoriam Arnold Rönnebeck", Undated (ca. 1947); typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 48)
    - "Is Peace Possible (French Point of View)". Typescript of lecture, 1946 November 6 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 49)
    - "Is U. S. High Commissioner John J. McCloy Throwing the Taxpayers' Money Away?", 1952; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 50)
    - "It is our Responsibility", 1942 December 21; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 51)
    - "Junior High School Organization, 2nd lecture, Oct. 29, 1946", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 52)
    - "Kampf der Banken gegen das Recht", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 53)
    - "Likes Roundup" (letter to the editor). Clipping, 1952 September 22 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 54)
    - "The Miracle of Burning Cologne". Writers War Board, Radio sketch, Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 55)
    - "My granddaughter Nicole", Undated; manuscript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 56)
    - "Neutrality Fatal" (letter to the editor), 1950 May 7; typescript and clipping (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 57)
    - "No Housing Shortage" (letter to the editor). Clipping, 1952 April 13 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 58)
    - "Noch eine Antwort". Clipping, 1939 December 16 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 59)
    - "Old Masters in a Shifting World". Typescript of lecture, 1943 November (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 60)
    - "Prevention of Juvenile Delinquency". Typescript of lecture, 1946 January 8 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 61)
    - "Punishment or Reeducation". Typescript of lecture, 1948 April 4 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 62)
    - "Reich Still Riddled by Ex-Nazis Plotting". Clipping, 1950 May 1 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 63)
    - "Sabotage of the Restitution Law", 1950 May; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 64)
    - "Secret Records in American Courts", ca. 1945; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 65)
    - "Sieg der Banken über die Rechtsprechung?", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 66)
    - Thomas Mann. Goethe und die Demokratie (review). Clipping, Autumn 1950 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 67)
    - "The Thunderstorm". Writers War Board, Radio sketch, Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 68)
    - "U.W.F. View Clarified" (letter to the editor). Clipping, 1950 May 2 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 69)
    - "West German Property". Clipping, 1956 July 14 (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 70)
    - "Western Germany", 1952 July 18; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 71)
    - "What Is Militarism?", ca. January/February 1951; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 72)
    - "What 'Going to Church' means to me", Undated (ca. 1950); typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 73)
    - "What Kind of Political and Economic Organization Do We Want Here in America and Do We Look Forward to in Europe?", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 74)
    - "Where are we Headed?", 1949 Spring; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 75)
      French version: "Où allons nous?" Typescript, undated.
    - "Wichtige Gesetzentwürfe im House of Representatives und Senate", 1956 March; typescript (Box 5 (4-Writings of Albert Lestoque), Folder 76)
- Family and general correspondence files, 1914-1960; 5; 103 file folders
  This series is divided into three sections: 1) family correspondence; 2) general individual correspondence; and 3) correspondence with organizations, newspapers, publishers. Albert Lestoque's correspondence with his brother, Paul Leser, spans the years 1932-1959. Additional correspondence between the brothers can also be found in the Paul Leser Papers.
  - Correspondence with family members, 1920-1959; 5.1
    - Coon, Bettina (daughter), 1955 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 1)
    - Hahn, Anna, 1937; 1940; Undated (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 2)
    - Leser, Bertha. Receipts, 1940-1941 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 3)
    - Leser, Helene (mother), 1920; 1924; 1935-1940 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 4)
    - Leser, Paul (brother), 1932; 1935; Undated (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 5)
    - Leser, Paul, 1936 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 6)
    - Leser, Paul, 1937 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 7)
    - Leser, Paul, 1938 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 8)
    - Leser, Paul, 1939 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 9)
    - Leser, Paul, 1940 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 10)
    - Leser, Paul. Correspondence concerning Paul Leser's immigration to the U.S., 1940-1941 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 11)
    - Leser, Paul, 1942 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 12)
    - Leser, Paul, 1948 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 13)
    - Leser, Paul, 1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 14)
    - Leser, Paul, 1950 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 15)
    - Leser, Paul, 1951 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 16)
    - Leser, Paul, 1953 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 17)
    - Leser, Paul, 1954 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 18)
    - Leser, Paul, 1955 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 19)
    - Leser, Paul, 1956 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 20)
    - Leser, Paul, 1957 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 21)
    - Leser, Paul, 1958 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 22)
    - Leser, Paul, 1959 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 23)
    - Lestoque (Schaber), Gerda, 1934; 1939; 1940; 1952; 1954 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 24)
    - Lestoque, Walter (son), 1940; 1957-1959; Undated (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 25)
    - Lestoque, Walter, 1960 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 26)
    - Lingemann, Heinrich, 1930; 1953; clippings (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 27)
    - Lingemann, Maria (Mira, sister), 1935-1938 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 28)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1940-1941 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 29)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1946-1950 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 30)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1951 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 31)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1952 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 32)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1953 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 33)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1954 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 34)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1955 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 35)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1956-1957 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 36)
    - Lingemann, Maria, 1959 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 37)
    - Schaber, Will, 1939 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 38)
  - General correspondence with individuals, 1932-1960; 5.2
    - Böckel, Wilhelm, 1954 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 39)
    - Brabazon of Tara, Lord, 1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 40)
    - Buckow, Imhoff, 1937; photos (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 41)
    - Condermann, Hans-Jürgen, 1948; 1950 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 42)
    - Fahr, Renate, 1955 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 43)
    - Fisher, Peter Thomas, 1952-1953 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 44)
    - Frankl, Heinrich, Undated (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 45)
    - George, Manfred (Aufbau), 1952-1958 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 46)
    - Gippert, Ferdinand (Pastor), 1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 47)
    - Guggenheim, Felix, 1952 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 48)
    - Hanau, Eduard, 1934-1941; 1956-1957 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 49)
    - Heger, Hans (Verlag), 1957 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 50)
    - Hellmer, Kurt, 1952-1953 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 51)
    - Hilger, Julie, 1932 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 52)
    - Höchberg, 1960 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 53)
    - Hoffman, Harry, 1954 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 54)
    - Lang, Josef, 1941 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 55)
    - Lederfine, Rena, 1950 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 56)
    - Lewis, Dorothy, 1955 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 57)
    - Lindsay, Martin, 1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 58)
    - Mayer, J., 1928 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 59)
    - Nelles, Karl, 1952-1953 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 60)
    - Pauli, Hanna, 1935-1957 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 61)
    - Pauli, Hermann, 1947; 1960 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 62)
    - Reinert, Hellmut, 1954-1957 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 63)
    - Reitlmeier, Margot, 1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 64)
    - Schaus, Agnes, 1948 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 65)